Sumeya Ibrahim

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full-Stack Developer with over a year of experience, specializing in Ruby on Rails, React, and JavaScript. Known for a strong ownership mindset and proficiency in backend technologies. Also brings excellent communication and collaboration skills, coupled with a passion for learning and adapting to new technologies.

EXPERIENCE

SELF EMPLOYED, Remote

Full-Stack developer | May 2023 - Present

- Collaborating with an average of 2-3 clients per month to understand their requirements and translate them into product features.
- Working closely with a team of 3-2 developers to implement an average of 30 desired changes and features per month.
- Conducting API integrations to connect the system with external services.
- Ensuring the responsiveness and functionality of the system across different devices and platforms.
- Participating in code reviews and providing feedback to maintain code quality and best practices.
- Troubleshooting and resolving any issues or bugs related to the system's functionality.
- Staying updated with industry trends and technologies to suggest improvements and enhancements to the system.

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL Projects, *Remote* **Web developer** | April 2023 – October 2023

Mastered intermediate to advanced topics in full-stack development while building 20+ full-stack and front-end projects independently and via pair programming (as a team).

 Harly-Davidson-Motors: An online web application that displays motorbikes. Users can reserve, add and remove motorbikes.

Built with: React, Redux and, Ruby on Rails Live demo:https://harley-davidson-73po.onrender.com/

• **Space-Travelers:** A front-end web application that displays SpaceX Rockets using external API. Users can reserve their favorite rockets and register for SpaceX missions.

Built with: JavaScript, Rest API, React, Redux Live demo: https://space-traverler-hub-1.vercel.app/

Portfolio
Github | Linkedin
sumeyaibrahim72@gmail.
com

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, Bootstrap

Back-End: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PHP, NodeJS, ExpressJS

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Figma, Render, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, JEST, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Adobe Illustrator

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

PROJECTS

Ethio-Tech

-Contributed to the development of a company website.

- Built with:(React, Redux, Tailwind, and ExpressJS)
- Live demo:

https://eat-k84f.onrender.com/

LINKS

Portfolio:

https://isume295.github .io/My Portfolio/ Github:

https://github.com/isum e295

LinkedIn:

http://www.linkedin.co m/in/sumeya-ibrahim

• **Comment Dish:** Platform for expressing your culinary opinions, exploring a wide variety of meals (utilizing external API), and sharing users thoughts with your words

Built with: HTML, CSS and, JavaScript

Live demo:

https://salimer.github.io/COMMENTDISH-project/dist/

MICROVERSE, Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) | April 2023 – June 2023

- Mentored a group of 2 junior web developers, and provided technical support through code reviews using Zoom and Slack communication tools.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation to result in 30% longevity in the program.

EchnoServe, A.A, Ethiopia

Intern | September 2022 – December 2022

- Designed an intuitive user interface (UI) for a mobile wallet web application, incorporating user-centered design principles and conducting usability tests with a sample of 30 users to ensure a seamless user experience.
- Implemented the UI design using the React.js framework, resulting in a responsive and interactive application that achieved a loading time of less than 2 seconds, contributing to high user satisfaction and engagement.
- Collaborated effectively with a cross-functional team of 8 developers, designers, and project managers, actively participating in daily stand-ups and contributing to the completion of the project within the designated timeline. Demonstrated strong teamwork skills by fostering open communication and resolving conflicts promptly to achieve project objectives.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE | March 2023 – Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Addis Ababa Science and Technology | September 2018–June 2022 Bachelor's Degree, Software Engineering

- Invested 4 years in learning various programming languages and software development tools in both practical and theoretical contexts.
- Gained hands-on experience by working on personal projects as well as collaborating with others on group projects.
- Earned a certificate of excellence for achieving high grades throughout my time at the university.